

CFMS 2018-19 President-elect Nominee

Name: Stephanie Smith

School: University of Calgary

Year of Study: 3/3



Bio/Letter of Intent (250 words max):

I am extremely fortunate to have served on the CFMS board over the past 6 months, as both the VP of Student Affairs and Executive VP. During this time, I have assessed if I would be a reasonable fit as the president. While I realize I still have a significant amount of material to absorb to be prepared to represent this amazing organization adequately, I assure you, I am passionately committed to professionally representing every single medical student across the country, based on our collaborative goals. I am motivated to support the education, advocacy, global health, financial and wellness resources available to students and intend to continue creating a safe, non-judgmental and transparent environment where students are encouraged to communicate their concerns, passions and ideas. I am inspired by medical students that have come forward to talk about mistreatment, stigma and barriers to their health. I believe we are entering an era that will thrive on a culture change. One where we all feel supported and safe in our classrooms and clinical environments, from the start of medical school until we are practicing physicians. I envision our generation of physicians, as those that challenge the long-standing norms and commit to both advancing our profession and moving us in a positive direction. I encourage you to not accept the status quo, yet advocate for a positive learning environment for our future generation. Let's ensure that what we are doing today, is getting us closer to where we want to be tomorrow.

CAPTAIN STEPHANIE SMITH, BN, RN, MA
Phone: (705) 716-9708 Email: stephanie.smith1@ucalgary.ca

EDUCATION

LDOCATION	
2016 Jul-present	Doctor or of Medicine. Cumming School of Medicine-University of Calgary.
2015 Aug-2016 Jun	French Language Program. Canadian Armed Forces Language School.
2012	Master of Arts – Disaster and Emergency Management Royal Roads University. Victoria, BC.
2006	Emergency Nursing Program. Halifax, NS.
2004	Bachelor of Nursing. University of New Brunswick. Fredericton, NB.
EMPLOYMENT	
Jul-Aug 2015	Senior Nursing Officer/Clinic Coordinator Trenton Cadet Camp Medical Clinic. Trenton, ON
Jun 2014 - Jun 2015	Officer Commanding (Manager) Treatment Company 1 Canadian Field Hospital. Petawawa. ON
Apr 2013 - May 2014	Clinical Training and Simulation Coordinator 1 Canadian Field Hospital. Petawawa, ON
Nov-Dec 2013	Senior Nursing Officer Disaster Assistance Response Team. Roxas City, Philippines
Oct 2011 - Mar 2013	Advanced Medical Technician Course Director Canadian Forces Health Services Training Centre. Borden, ON
May-Sept 2011	Nursing Officer Clinical Phase Training Coordinator Canadian Forces Health Services Training Centre. Borden, ON
Nov 2009 - Apr 2011	Basic Nursing Officer Course Director Canadian Forces Health Services Training Centre. Borden, ON
Apr-Oct 2009	Critical Care Nursing Officer Role 3 Multinational Medical Unit (ICU & ER). Kandahar, Afghanistan
Jan-Mar 2009	Pediatric Intensive Care Unit Nurse Children's Hospital of Eastern Ontario. Ottawa, ON
Sep 2007- Dec 2008	Intensive Care Unit Nurse Ottawa Hospital-Civic Campus. Ottawa, ON
Jan – Aug 2007	Medical Surgical Nursing Officer Role 3 Multinational Medical Unit. Kandahar, Afghanistan
Jan-Aug 2006	General Surgery Nurse Ottawa Hospital-Civic Campus. Ottawa, ON

Jan-Dec 2005 Orthopedic Surgical Nurse

Ottawa Hospital-General Campus. Ottawa, ON

Apr-Dec 2004 *Medical-Surgical Nurse*

Oromocto Public Hospital. Oromocto, NB

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

2017 Sept-	Vice President Student Affairs & Executive VP
Present	Canadian Federation of Medical Students
2016 Sept-	Vice President External Affairs
Present	Calgary Medical Student Association
2016 Sept-	University of Calgary Medical Student Representative
Present	Alberta Medical Association Committee on Student Affairs
2017 April-	Medical Student Representative
2018 Feb	Alberta Medical Association Board
2017 Feb-	Medical Student Representative
2018 Feb	College of Physicians and Surgeons of Alberta Board
004== 1	
2015 Feb-	Pembroke Regional Hospital Fundraising Committee-
2016 Jun	Garrison Petawawa Military Representative
0045.0-4	One discolute metional Medical Deliat One microtica
2015 Oct	Canadian International Medical Relief Organization
	Gazientep, Turkey
2014-2016	Red Cross Emergency Responder/ Disaster and Emergency Response
2014-2010	Educator
	Pembroke, Ontario
	i elibione, Olitano
2013-2016	Garrison Petawawa Triathlon Coach
2010 2010	
2010-2013	Base Borden Triathlon Coach
2012 Apr	Bernard Mevs Hospital-ER and Adult ICU
•	Port au Prince, Haiti
2011 Dec	Bernard Mevs Hospital-Pediatric ICU
	Port au Prince, Haiti

QUALIFICATIONS

- Advanced Cardiac Life Support Instructor
- Trauma Nursing Core Course Instructor
- International Trauma Life Support Pediatric Course Instructor
- International Trauma Life Support Advanced Course Instructor
- Health Care Provider CPR Instructor
- STRIVE Resiliency Instructor and Coordinator
- Medical Simulation Facilitator and Operator
- Pediatric Fundamental Critical Care Support Course
- Emergency Nursing Pediatric Course
- Pediatric Advanced Life Support Course